### PAIKTRA NOM

(651)983-3133 ♦ paiktranom@gmail.com ♦ paiktranom.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with 3 years of experience in providing frontend development and deployment. Proven success in requirements gathering to determine project scope, identify bugs, and put out a product that puts customers first. Experienced in working with Python, Javascript, and Jira to fulfill project needs. Displays extensive knowledge of agile methodologies, git methodologies, and process design.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Land Processing Distributed Active Archive Center (LP DAAC), USGS September 2020 - June 2023 Software Engineer I

- · Design solutions by identifying client pain points and assisting scientists with more efficient goal achievement in the ASTER mission.
- · Conducted updates on 100+ outdated libraries within several programming languages by applying cutting edge and best engineering methodologies, ensuring 12 different enterprise-level applications were updated and future-proofed.
- · Applied Sprint methodology to help with organization of active tasks while transitioning to sAFE methodology for more efficient project management in the future.
- · Identified and resolved issues in ASTER tools by surveying bug reports and feature suggestions to effectively design user-centered tools without disrupting productivity.
- · Coordinated with NASA scientists in requirements gathering for the creation of 150+ Jira tickets for new features and further maintenance of ASTER tools.

## EROS CalVal Center of Excellence, USGS Software Engineer Intern.

June 2020 - September 2020

- · Research for georeferencing design using Landsat 8 data to attach a geographical coordinate system to an aerial image for georeferencing automation development.
- · Design an algorithm with Python scripting and using the ArcGIS API for automated production of georeferenced images.
- · Create weekly presentations to present progress of development with tasks to aim for in the upcoming week.

### **PROJECTS**

## LP DAAC External Website Software Engineer

September 2020 - June 2023 https://lpdaac.usgs.gov

- · Actively engaged in creating new features and maintaining the website for over 200,000 monthly visitors.
- · Collaborated in a 4 person team to improve the user experience for LPDAAC scientists to create news articles, ASTER Products, and E-Learning pages.
- · Overhauled the publications table to improve loading times by 10% as it parses over 10,000 publications.
- · Initiated the creation of the podcasts page by manipulating Django to interface with Wagtail CMS. Allowing visitors another resource for obtaining information on different NASA missions such as ECOSTRESS and EMIT.

### **EDUCATION**

#### South Dakota State University, Brookings, SD

August 2017 - May 2021

B.E., Computer Science with Minors in Mathematics and Software Engineering

### TECHNICAL ABILITIES

Languages: C, C++, C#, Python, HTML5, CSS, Javascript, PHP, Perl

Frameworks: Django, Flask, ASP.Net MVC, Wagtail CMS

Tools: Docker, Kubernetes, Jira, Acunetix

Databases: PostgresSQL

Cloud Technologies: AWS

Version Control: Github, GitLab

### **AWARDS**

- · Graduated university with Magna Cum Laude distinction: 2021
- · Deans list for 5 semesters.